Guide to the Charles H. Irby Papers, 1962-1975
Department of Special Collections
- DCE, RWW, Norton. SRI. "The Augmented knowledge workshop." National Computer Conference, 1973. Journal doc. #14724. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- DCE. "SRI-ARC summary for IPT contractor-meeting." Jan. 11, 1974. Journal doc.#13537. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Appendix E: Software-engineering augmentation system, from "SRI proposal for research ISU 71-94. Oct. 18, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- "A Look at the MPS conversion." Mar. 22, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- "Online team environment." SRI-ARC plans. June 8, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Announcement for meeting about short-term military use of software. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- "Software production facility conference." Conference notes. July 25, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Meeting notes for FORUM conference for the Software Production Facility group. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Network Graphics Group folder: (Box 7, Folder 2)
- PADLIPSKY. "Graphics meeting report." NWG/RFC #282, NIC #8164. Dec. 8, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- JGM, COTTON, KELLEY, LIDDLE, MEYER. "Graphics protocol." Jan. 15, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Letter to JGM, PADLISPSKY from E. Harslam, RAND Corp., re. graphics programs over network. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- COTTON. "Network graphic attention-handling." Apr. 5, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- LPD. Xerox-PARC. "DEC PDP-10 -- IMLAC communcation system." RFC #190, NIC #7135, July 13, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- PELTAN. Mit-Project MAC. "Hardware status of the MIT MAC - DM/CG/CN IMLAC displays." Aug. 16, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- MOORER. "DPY - a device independent graphics package." SU-AI. Operating note No. 63. Nov. 12, 1970. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- BAUMGART. "GEOMED - a geometric editor." (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Memo re. "graphics hardware, software, and representations currently in use at SU-AI..." n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- JGM. "Muddle graphics." June 1971. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Network graphics meeting. Schedule of events. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- CROCKER. "Proposal for a network standard format for a data stream to control graphics display." NWG/RFC #86, NIC 5631, Jan. 5, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- METCALFF. "Some historic moments in networking." NWG/RFC #89, NIC 5697. Jan. 19, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- HARSLAM amd HEAFNER. "Some thoughts on network graphics." NWG/RFC #94, NIC 5725, Feb. 3, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- McCONNELL. "Response to RFC #86, Proposal for network standard format for a graphics data stream." NWG/RFC #125, NIC #5841, Apr. 18, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- McCONNELL. NWG/RFC #126, NIC #5842. Apr. 18,1971. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- POSTEL and CERF. "UCLA-Computer science graphics overview." NWG/RFC #174, NIC #6799, June 8, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- McCONNELL. "Device independent graphic display description." NWG/RFC #177, NIC #7102, June 15, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- McCONNELL. "Modifications to RFC #177." NWG/RFC #181, NIC #7124, June 27, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- KELLEY. Univ. of Illinois. "Proposed graphic display modes." NWG/RFC #184, NIC #7128, July 6, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- MICHENER. "A Network graphics leader." NWG/RFC #186, NIC 7130, July 12, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- "Graphics implementation and conceptualization at ARC." RFC #191, NIC #7136, July 13, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- RWW. "Some factors which a Network Graphics Protocol must consider." NWG/RFC #192, NIC #7137. July 12, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- "Video graphic hardware configuation." (Box 7, Folder 6)
- VEZZA. "Network graphics meeting." NWG/RFC #134, NIC #6711, Apr. 29, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- MEYER. "Graphics on multics." July 12, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- VEZZA. MIT Project MAC. Bibliography for the Network Graphics Meeting. July 12, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- MICHENER. "Network graphics leader." NWG/RFC #186, July 12, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- ANDREWS, LEHTMAN, and WHP. "Tree Meta -- a metacompiler for the Augmentation Research Center." Preliminary draft., 25 March, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- WHP. "L|0, a programming language for the Augmentation Research Center." May 29, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- "Terminal System Character Generators." May 19, 1972., (2 copies) (Box 7, Folder 9)
- FAIRBAIRN. "Terminal system/character generator interfaces." Inter-office memo, Xerox-PARC. April 4, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- "Experimental character generator." c1971. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- McCRACKEN. "Revolution in an overview." Datamation, vol. 19, no. 12 (Dec. 1973). p. 50-52. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- DONALDSON. "Structured progamming." Datamation, vol. 19, no. 12 (Dec. 1973). p. 52-54. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- MILLER and LINDAMOOD. "Structured programming: top-down approach." Datamation, vol. 19, no. 12 (Dec. 1973). p. 55-59. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Report on form systems. Dec. 29, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- BWL, JGM, and Satterthwaite. "Abstract for 'On the transfer of control between context.'" n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- "Notes about running standalone L|0 programs." Oct. 11, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- "CML final report." Feb. 25, 1975. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- "TENEX NCP Finite state machine for connections." TENEX memo no. 155. RFC #689, NIC #32656, May 23, 1975. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- CLARK. "Linguistic contribution to GOTO-less programming." Datamation, vol. 19, no. 12 (Dec. 1973). p. 62-3. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- WILBUR. "POST - Mail subsystem." Dec. 29, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- "TENEX user's guide, TENEX TECO." Jan. 1963. p. 167-176. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- "Appendix C" to unknown document. p. C - 1-9. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- "ISI Video terminal system software porposal." Draft. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Report re. ARC's envisioned changes and extensions to NLS. July 25, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- STROLLO. "TENEX calendar system." Mar. 14, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- "Preliminary design of new NLS file system..." Dec. 29, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- "Preliminary design of new NLS file system which allows backlinks, comments, archiving, and serves as a base for implementing sets." Jan. 20, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- "Statement property lists." An approach to provide a property list data structure with each statement in an NLS file. June 1, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- WHP. "Basic file system." Mar. 2, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- "Some basic concepts in software support of graphics consoles in a timesharing system." May 13, 1971. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- DUVALL. "VTS font handling." Mar. 13, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- DUVALL. "Design notes for the Video Terminal System: input/output servicing." June 26, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- LPD and BWL. "Input protocol." Inter-office memo, XeroxPARC, July 5, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- DUVALL. "Design notes for the Video Terminal System: processes, process communication, and scheduling." July 4, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- LPD and BWL. "Design notes for video terminal display (VTS) display software." Inter-office memo, Xerox-PARC, May 25, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- DUVALL. Memo describing the user characteristics of the VTS. June 19, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- DUVALL. "Design notes for the Video Terminal System: memory allocation." July 2, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- DUVALL. "VTS display primitives." Mar. 13, 1973. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- SRI Intercom. no. 251 (Apr. 11, 1975). (Box 8, Folder 1)
- "Proposed specification of Inter-site message protocol." July 8, 1975. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- "Network Information Center and computer-augmented team interaction." SRI-ARC. RADC-TR-71-175, June 1971. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- POSTEL. "New protocols." Version 2. SRI-ARC. Nov. 22, 1974. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- "Thinking man's computer may revolutionize job habits." SRI Reprints of selected news items. no. 10-1972. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- ANDREWS, CHI, POGGOI, RWW. SRI-ARC. "User interface system for a computer network marketplace." Nov. 15, 1976. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- ANDREWS, GARLICK, POGGIO. SRI-ARC. "Frontend system documentation." Jan. 5, 1977. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- ANDREWS, BOLI, POGGIO." SRI-ARC. "Guide to the command meta language and the command language interpreter." Jan. 5, 1977. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- ANDREWS, BOLI, POGGIO. SRI-ARC. "Introduction to the frontend." Jan. 5, 1977. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- "User interface system for a computer network marketplace." n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- CHI, CFD, KEV. "Command meta language for NLS." June 28, 1974. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- CHI. SRI-ARC. "Command Language System.", (8 copies) (Box 8, Folder 5)
- CHI. Computer program. July 21, 1975. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Black binder marked "TENEX" (Box 8, Folder 5)
- BBN. "TENEX JSYS Manual." NIC #19031. Sept. 1, 1973 (revision). (Box 8, Folder 5)
- "JSYS 400, Section 9." Downloaded May 1974. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Digital Equipment Corporation. "PDP10 reference handbook." 1970. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- SRI-NIC. "ARPANET protocol handbook." Prepared for Defense Communications Agency. NIC 7104. Rev. 1, Apr. 1976. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Message Committee. Interim report. Jan. 30, 1975. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- "Command Meta Language." Oct. 24, 1974. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- "Display techniques for interactive text manipulation." National Computer Conference, 1974., (2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 3)
- ANDREWS. "Line processor - a device for amplification of display terminal capabilities fpr text manipulation." National Computer Conference, 1974. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- TNLS-8 Quick Reference. SRI-ARC. Sept. 1, 1974. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Items re. submission of the paper "Command Meta Language System" for 1976 National Computer Conference. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Information automation project, USC/ISI."Military Message Processing System Design." Jan. 10, 1975. (Box 9, Folder 5-8)
Acronyms and Names
Acronyms
ARC
Augmentation Research Center at SRI
ARPA
Advanced Research Projects Agency
BBN
Bolt, Beranek and Newman
CML
Control Meta Language
DPS
Distributed Programming System
MPS
Modular Programming System
NIC
Network Information Center at SRI
NSW
National Software Works
NWG
Network Working Group
OSM
Operating System Module
SRI
Stanford Research Institute
USC-ISI
University of Southern California - Information Sciences Institute
Names
BWL
Butler W. Lampson
CFD
Charles F.Dornbush
CHI
Charles H. Irby
Cotton
Cotton, Ira
DCE
D. C. Engelbart
JGM
James G. Mitchell
JEW
James E. White
Kelley
Kelley, Karl
KEV
Kenneth E. Victor
Liddle
Liddle, Dave
LPD
Peter Deutsch
Michener
Michener, Jim
Meyer
Meyer, Ed
RWW
Richard W. Watson
WHP
William H. Paxton.